AKRAM ABU KHOUSA

Palestine, Gaza, +970

</>

(595) 527 040

</>

akram.khousa@gmail.com

CAREER PROFILE

Creative Web Developer with 40 months experience in creating cutting edge Websites for eight persons by creating over 300,000 Lines of Code as a consequence of over 7,400 hours of hard work in the programming of 18 projects implemented by six programming Languages during study and real works. In addition, 280 hours as a Team Leader for study projects.

Core competencies include Front-End Development (HTML, CSS, JavaScript and React JS), Back-End Development (Python and Django Framework), REST API Framework, GraphQL, Versioning Control Systems (Git), Docker Containerization, Unit Testing, System Analysis, Software Design, UI/UX Design, and TeamWork.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Open Screenplay. Toronto, Canada

08/2019 to Present

Open Screenplay is the world's first platform and community where storytellers and screenwriters can learn, build a profile, write individually or collaborate, and get paid and produced.

ROLE: Full Stack React-JS Developer (08/2019)

Frontend developer: HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, React-JS framework, NextJS, building reusable components, integrating with external Apps and APIs, and converting UI/UX wireframes into code.

Backend developer: Python – Django framework, Database management – MySQL, Platform's Payment System, REST framework,

Test Driven Development, Platform Upgrade process, and Performance Enhancements and Code Refactoring.

Ministry of Telecom. & IT. Gaza, Palestine

06/2018 to 09/2018

ROLE: Technical Engineer (06/2018)

Responsible for Network Management, Router-band programming and Windows Server Coadministration.

UAWC Org. Gaza, Palestine

05/2016 to 01/2017

Union of Agricultural Work Committees is an organization supporting the agricultural fields and grant foundations for evolving.

ROLE: Computer Engineer (05/2016)

Responsible for Technical Supporting and Data Entry.

EDUCATION

Al Azhar University, Gaza, 2020.

B.A., Computer Systems Engineering. (Degree - **89.6%**)

Technical course – AWS - Cloud Partitioner (11/2022).

Technical course – Node.Js, Express Framework Development (11/2021).

Technical course – Docker Containerization (06/2021).

Technical course – GraphQL Technology [JS Apollo/Python Graphene] (04/2021).

Technical course – JavaScript, ReactJS Framework Development (09/2019).

Technical course – Python, Django Framework Development (06/2019).

Technical course – Git and Versioning Control systems (05/2019).

Training course – The Art of Dialogue and Facilitation (10/2018).

Technical course – UI/UX Design complete course (01/2018).

Training course – Fundamental Skills and Qualities of Civic Leadership (10/2017).

Training course – Communications and Presentation Skills (06/2017).

Technical course – Website Development (05/2015).

EXTRACURRICULAR & VOLUNTEER ACTIVITIES

Al-Nayzak Org., Gaza, 06/2017 to 11/2017

Social Activities, Volunteer – Served as [Team Supporting & Data Entry].

Social Initiative, Gaza, 11/2017

Initiative for supporting people who have disabilities, Team Leader – Served as [supporting, Logistics & coordinator].

Portfolio Links

https://github.com/akramakh

https://www.behance.net/akramakh

https://akramakh.github.io/me